uca.ac.uk 2018-01-30

# University for the Creative Arts - Privacy Policy - UCA

**GENERAL** This privacy statement sets out how the University for the Creative Arts (the ‘University’) complies with European Union data protection requirements and how it uses and protects any personal information that you provide when you use this website. If you have any questions about this policy or do not agree with it, please contact the University at [**web@uca.ac.uk**](mailto:web@uca.ac.uk)

The University may change this policy, from time to time, by updating this page. You should check this page from time to time to ensure you are happy with any changes.

For your protection, the University is registered under the Data Protection Act 1998 and has given all appropriate notifications to the Information Commissioner.

 **WHAT WE COLLECT**

We may collect the following information:

  * Name, address, telephone number, email address and your credit card information.
  * Internal record keeping
  * Administering and operating the website
  * To improve our services
  * To contact you about new services or other information which we think you may find interesting
  * To contact you for market research purposes
  * We may contact you by email, phone or mail unless you have registered with the appropriate Preference Service.

**WHAT DO WE DO WITH THE INFORMATION WE GATHER?**

We require this information to provide you with a better service; and, in particular, for the following reasons:

 **DIRECT MARKETING**

We would like to provide you with information about new services, programmes of study, University events, special offers and other information which we think you may find interesting. We may send you such information by mail or telephone unless you have registered with the appropriate Preference Service. When you provide us with information, you will be given the option to let us know that you do not want your information used for direct marketing purposes. If you request this option, we will not send you any direct marketing.

You may change your mind at any time by contacting our Data Protection Compliance Officer at the University for the Creative Arts, Falkner Road, Farnham, Surrey GU9 7DS.

 **EMAIL MARKETING**

We would also like to provide you with the information above by email. However, we appreciate that email ‘spam’ has become a problem in recent years.

If you have previously asked us to send you information on our services, we may send you information on our range of services by email, unless you have asked us not to do so.

If the reason you have given us personal information is to receive email information from us, we will continue to provide this information by email unless you ask us not to do so.

Otherwise, when you provide us with personal information, we will ask you whether or not you are happy for us to send you this kind of information by email.

If you decide at any time that you no longer wish to receive marketing emails from us, please contact our Data Protection Compliance Officer at the University for the Creative Arts, Falkner Road, Farnham, Surrey GU9 7DS.

 **WHO WE SHARE THE INFORMATION WITH, AND YOUR CHOICES**

When you use this site and have not advised us to the contrary, you are agreeing that we may use your personal information for the purposes set out in this statement.

We may transfer, disclose, sell, distribute or lease your personal information to third parties, unless you tell us that you do not wish this to happen. This may include direct marketing agents.

 **WHAT IF YOU THINK WE HAVE INCORRECT INFORMATION, OR YOU WOULD LIKE A COPY OF THE INFORMATION WE HOLD ABOUT YOU?**

You may request details of personal information which we hold about you under the Data Protection Act 1998. A small fee will be payable. If you would like a copy of the information held on you, please write to:

Data Protection Compliance Officer,University for the Creative Arts, Falkner Road, Farnham, Surrey GU9 7DS

If you believe that any information we are holding on you is incorrect or incomplete, please write or email us as soon as possible to the above address. We will correct any information which was found to be incorrect promptly.

 **SECURITY**

We are committed to ensuring that your information is secure. In order to prevent unauthorised access or disclosure, we have put in place suitable physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online. We use encryption when collecting or transferring sensitive data, such as credit card information.

 **OTHER WEBSITES**

This website may contain links to enable you to visit other websites, of interest, easily. However, once you have used these links to leave our site, you should note that we do not have any control over that other website. Therefore, we cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information which you provide whilst visiting such sites, and such sites are not governed by this Privacy Statement. You should exercise caution and look at the privacy statement applicable to the website in question.

 **HOBSONS PLC & GECKO LABS  
**The University for the Creative Arts has a relationship with Hobsons Plc and Gecko Labs Limited for the following activities:

  * Customer Relationship Management system
  * Web form management
  * Data collection for 
    * Prospectus requests
    * Open Days
    * Enquiries
  * Live Chat
  * Event management

**HOW WE USE COOKIES**

A cookie is a piece of text which asks permission to be placed on your computer's hard drive. Once you agree, your browser adds that text in a small file. A cookie helps analyse web traffic or lets you know when you visit a particular site. Cookies allow web applications to respond to you as an individual. The web application can tailor its operations to your needs, likes and dislikes by gathering and remembering information about your preferences.

We use traffic log cookies to identify which pages are being used. This helps us analyse data about web page traffic and improve our website in order to tailor it to customer needs. We only use this information for statistical analysis purposes and then the data is removed from the system. Denial of a traffic log cookie should not prevent you from using one of these sites.

Overall, cookies help us provide you with a better website, by enabling us to monitor which pages you find useful and which you do not. A cookie in no way gives us access to your computer or any information about you, other than the data you choose to share with us. This practice is strictly in force. We know that people have concerns about cookies, but we believe that the benefit we both gain from their proper use is worthwhile. You may set your web browser to notify you of cookie placement requests or decline cookies completely. You can delete the files that contain cookies - those files are stored as part of your internet browser.
